<resources>
    <string name="app_name">iPro Lyfstyle beta</string>
    <string name="title_activity_register">RegisterActivity</string>
    <string name="title_activity_home_screen">iPro Lyfstyle</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="nav_header_title">iPro Lifestyle</string>
    <string name="nav_header_subtitle">sauvikraycs@gmail.com</string>
    <string name="nav_header_desc">Navigation header</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="Fragment_fitness">Fitness</string>
    <string name="Fragment_diet">Diet Plan</string>
    <string name="Fragment_shopping">Shopping Ideas</string>
    <string name="Fragment_books">Books</string>
    <string name="Fragment_quotes">Quotes</string>
    <string name="Plan_fitness">So you want to get strong, and you have no idea how to start.

You probably feel like the cat in the image above, and you’re thinking to yourself, “dumbbells, push-ups, squats. These are terms I’ve HEARD before, but how do I combine them into a workout to get in shape? HALP.”

I got you.

If you haven’t already done so, I would consider checking out our previous posts in our Strength 101 series:

Strength Training 101: An Introduction
Strength Training 101: Equipment
Strength Training 101: Finding the right gym.
If you’re a woman, you know that you won’t get bulky from lifting weights!
And if you’ve read those things, you also know the following:

A strong body is a healthy body.

You know you SHOULD be strength training regularly, but let’s be honest: starting a whole new way of working out can be daunting. It’s the reason so many people stick to the same old habits (that don’t work).

I know this stuff is scary, and if you don’t know how to get started or are looking for more specific instruction, we got you covered.

In addition to the free resource you’ll read below, we also offer 1-on-1 Online Coaching, where you’ll get personalized instruction and accountability from a Coach on Team Nerd FitnessBODYWEIGHT TRAINING

The first option is bodyweight training. With bodyweight training you need minimal equipment (or none at all), and you can train from anywhere.  It doesn’t matter if you’re at home, in a hotel, at a playground, in your office at work,  or traveling around the world, as long as you have enough space to move around, you can get your workout done (and fit it into a busy schedule).

If you’re bodyweight training, grab a pull-up bar or a set of gymnastics rings (these can help you make exercises both easier and harder depending on your level).  If you’re just starting out, an exercise band to help assist you with movements such as pull ups or dips.

However – none of these are necessary, you can easily do bodyweight training without any equipment at all. The downside to bodyweight exercises is that you will need to consistently modify the exercise’s difficulty in order to ensure you are leveling up and progressing.

DUMBBELL TRAINING

Dumbbells are a great way to start out with weighted strength training for a few reasons. First, most gyms will have a good set dumbbells, even if it’s a basic gym in your apartment complex. If you want to train at home, you can get a set of adjustable dumbbells that don’t take up a ton of space.

Second, dumbbells make it easy to add a small amount of weight to a movement, and dumbbell exercises can seem less intimidating than barbell training.  On top of that, starting with a 45 lb barbell might be too much weight at first.  Dumbbells  also have an added stabilization challenge, and point out muscle imbalances pretty easily.

If you can’t finish a rep, it’s much easier to drop a dumbbell than it is to drop a barbell. As a newbie learning the movements, this might be helpful.

The biggest downside about dumbbells?  You may outgrow whatever set you purchase fairly quickly, and heavy dumbbells can get costly. A gym membership with dumbbells that go up to (or over) 100 lbs should help solve this problem.

BARBELL TRAINING

The barbell workout is my personal favorite. If your goal is strength above all else, this is the option that we recommend. Barbells allow you to progress clearly and quickly, allowing you to add small increments of weight each week.

Because a barbell is incredibly stable (using two hands instead of just one with a dumbbell), it’s also much easier to go heavy – especially for lower body movements like the squat and the deadlift. For exercises like the squat or the press, you can use racks to safely load and deload heavy weights.

The biggest downside to barbell training is that in order to do it at home, you need to have a squat rack, a barbell, a bench, and enough weight in your house or garage (which is not an inexpensive investment when you’re starting out).</string>
</resources>
